<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.geocausa.RufusArm64</id>
  <name>RufusArm64</name>
  <summary>Create bootable USB drives on Ubuntu ARM64</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>RufusArm64 is an unofficial bootable-USB creator designed for Ubuntu on ARM64 computers.</p>
    <p>It writes raw and ISOHybrid media, prepares compressed and common virtual-disk inputs, creates Windows installation media, verifies signed acquisition catalogs, analyzes UEFI and Secure Boot metadata, and provides guarded persistent-live creation with optional ARM64 boot-time media-integrity validation.</p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.geocausa.RufusArm64.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/geocausa/RufusUbuntuArm64</url>
  <developer id="io.github.geocausa">
    <name>RufusArm64 contributors</name>
  </developer>
  <provides>
    <binary>rufusarm64</binary>
    <binary>rufusarm64-persistence</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.12.1" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes packaged GTK startup on desktops that provide both GTK 3 and GTK 4 introspection by pinning GTK 3 before integrated dialog imports.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.0" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Adds the guarded graphical drive-image backup workflow and closes audited privilege, progress-channel, process-reaping, and report-validation edge cases before the Stage 1 release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Adds descriptor-safe UEFI, DBX, and SBAT analysis plus an opt-in, reproducibly built ARM64 boot-time media-integrity validator for supported persistent Ubuntu/Debian writable-copy media, qualified under pinned AArch64 QEMU firmware and explicitly unsigned.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.6" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Prevents desktop automount races during persistent-live USB creation by setting and verifying the GPT do-not-automount attribute before FAT32 and ext4 formatting.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.5" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Completes the pre-parity safety and correctness audit with stronger identity, arithmetic, GPT durability, acquisition, GUI concurrency, static-analysis, Debian-policy, and reproducible-package gates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.4" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes persistence analysis for the official Ubuntu 26.04 ARM64 desktop image's harmless root-self alias while preserving strict escape, nested-root, and cycle rejection.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.3" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Consolidates the desktop experience to one visible RufusArm64 application entry with a Create Persistent Live USB action, while retaining the separate guarded persistence helper internally.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.2" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes persistent-live analysis and verified FAT32 copying for bounded in-tree directory links such as Canonical images' dists/stable metadata path, while retaining escape and cycle rejection.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.1" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Aligns persistence analysis with the fresh GPT/FAT32/ext4 creator layout, fixes Canonical Resolute concept-image compatibility, and removes reliance on embedded ISOHybrid MBR geometry.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Adds the guarded graphical persistent-live USB wizard, identity-bound read-only analysis and creation, modern Ubuntu casper cmdline support, reboot qualification records, and the threshold-signed built-in acquisition-channel foundation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Adds signed image acquisition, richer diagnostics, and a guarded CLI-only experimental Linux persistence workflow with verified GPT, FAT32, ext4, boot-file, and media-copy operations.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <p>Adds compressed and virtual-disk preparation, Microsoft DBX updates, PE/COFF revocation checks, and target-sized expansion limits.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Adds true x86/x86-64 Windows BIOS/CSM media, Windows PE driver auto-loading, source hashing, strict symlink-safe driver copies, and pinned legacy boot-code verification.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Adds manual FAT32/NTFS selection, verified Rufus UEFI:NTFS media, NTFS checks, and optional Windows driver-folder staging.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.2" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Adds GPT/MBR UEFI selection, FAT32 cluster-size controls, full formatting, a one-pass media check, and clearer From-image behavior.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Responsive graphical ARM64 release with Windows Setup options, compact WIM progress, direct partition detection, a bundled WIM engine, and expanded safety tests.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
